Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we have a
delicious lesson all about
Chinese food for you.
That's right.
Today we are ordering Chinese food.
Now for many of you listeners that are
actually Chinese, you may not recognize these
dishes because we are talking
about American Chinese food.
That's right.
So long ago people
came over to America from
mainly Hong Kong
and so a lot of the food
we have is kind of more
like Hong Kong food.
Cantonese food.
But it's also very American.
So let's take a listen to today's dialogue
and find out exactly what we are eating.
Hi, welcome to Happy Buddha.
Can I get you anything to drink?
Coke for me please.
I'll have a Sprite.
Okay, I'll go get that for you.
Are there any questions with the menu?
Do you use MSG?
No ma'am.
MSG-free.
Oh man, I haven't had
Chinese food in so long.
I want everything.
This place has the best sesame chicken.
Yeah, I've been craving
Chinese for such a long time.
I used to get takeout all the time.
It's definitely been a while.
Let's start off with some crab wrangoon.
Oh yeah, that sounds good.
I think I'm going to get
these sesame chicken
with fried rice, a spring
roll and egg drop soup.
So tempting to order everything on
the menu, it all looks so appetizing.
I think I'll get general
toast chicken, hot
and sour soup, fried
wontons, and white rice.
Aren't you supposed to be on a diet?
You should at least get brown rice.
I don't think so.
I hate brown rice and I'm so
sick of eating healthy all the time.
I've been eating so much salad.
I swear I've forgotten
what meat tastes like.
There's no better remedy than some
nice, greasy, calorie-laden Chinese food.
I might even get in order of broccoli beef.
Oh gosh, I'm so hungry.
Let's call the waitress over.
All right, we're back.
So obviously everything seems so
good, very typical American Chinese dishes.
And we have a lot of things
that we can take a look at.
So let's start with language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
In language takeaway
today, we're going to be
talking about some
general food words, words
that you can use when
you're ordering food.
So the first time we should
talk about is this MSG.
Right, Andrea asks, do you use MSG?
So why is she asking this and what is MSG?
MSG is an ingredient in foods.
It's kind of like a
condiment, something that
you put on the food after
the food has been cooked.
And it makes the food
taste better, brighter.
It intensifies the flavors a little bit.
Yeah, and it looks like salt or sugar.
It's on the tables usually
at Chinese restaurants.
But a lot of people don't
like MSG because they
don't think it's very
safe for their bodies.
And so actually the
waitress says that the
food is MSG free, which
means there's no MSG in it.
That's right.
Okay.
So she says, our food is MSG
free, which is this, this chemical,
I think it's kind of like a
chemical that you described.
That's right.
And a lot of people don't want that.
So you can ask, is this food MSG free?
Mm hmm.
You could also ask, is it fat free?
Right.
Is it salt free?
This is a very helpful way of asking
about what the ingredients are in a dish.
That's right.
And actually, Manny is
talking about the food as well.
And he says, yeah, I've been
craving Chinese for such a long time.
Okay.
So the verb here is to crave,
but he said he's been craving.
So he really has been wanting
this food for a long time.
So if you say, I'm craving Italian
food, what does that mean?
That means I really
want to eat Italian food.
You feel like having Italian food.
That's right.
I'm craving some kind of food.
I really want to eat it.
Okay.
And he said that he used
to get takeout all the time.
So he's obviously talking
about Chinese food.
What does it mean by takeout?
Well, takeout is the opposite of sitting
down in a restaurant in eating food.
Takeout is what you do when
you want to go home and eat it.
So in many restaurants,
you can order the
food and then you go and you pick
up the food and you bring it home.
Okay.
So that's takeout.
So it's a noun you get takeout, right?
But it's a little bit different
from a different kind of takeout.
There's takeout where you order the food
and you pick it up and you bring it home.
But there's also delivery
and delivery is when
you order the food
and someone else brings
it to you.
Okay.
So be careful with those too.
All right.
Very good.
And moving forward,
and moving forward, many
kept talking about
the food and said, wow,
everything on the menu
looks so appetizing.
It all looks so appetizing.
Okay.
Appetizing is a way to describe something.
In this case, we're describing food.
So that's normally how
we use the word appetizing.
So appetizing basically
means that you're
excited about eating this food
because it looks like it will be good.
So what about the word appetizer?
Does this have anything to do with it?
I think appetizer is something
that makes you want to eat more.
That's why it's at the beginning of a meal.
You have your appetizer before
you have your main course.
But the word appetizing
means that it's very appealing.
You really want to eat it.
It looks good.
It looks delicious.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Very good.
And Andrea was worried because
many is ordering so much food.
She asks, aren't you
supposed to be on a diet?
Okay.
So this is a phrase and I want to remind
everyone to keep this phrase in mind.
You can, um, you can diet, which is a
verb, but in this case, you're on a diet.
So it's a noun.
I'm on a diet.
I'm trying to eat healthily.
I'm trying to watch the
things that I put in my body.
So usually if you're
on a diet, you don't eat
really greasy, fatty, tiny,
take out Chinese food.
You eat salads and soups.
Okay.
So you are on a diet.
Yes.
He's on a diet or I was
on a diet, but I stopped.
All right.
A lot of great appealing food.
Why don't we go and
listen to our dialogue
again and we'll be back
with language takeaway
part two, but we're going to take a look
at the specific American Chinese dishes.
Hi.
Welcome to Happy Buddha.
Can I get you anything to drink?
Coke for me, please.
I'll have a Sprite.
Okay.
I'll go get that for you.
Are there any questions with the menu?
Do you use MSG?
No, ma'am.
We are MSG free.
Oh, man, I haven't had
Chinese food in so long.
I want everything.
This place has the best sesame chicken.
Yeah.
I've been craving Chinese
for such a long time.
I used to get takeout all the time.
It's definitely been a while.
Let's start off with some crab wrangoon.
Oh, yeah.
That sounds good.
I think I'm going to
get the sesame chicken
with fried rice, a spring
roll, and egg drop soup.
It's so tempting to order
everything on the menu.
It all looks so appetizing.
I think I'll get general
toast chicken, hot
and sour soup, fried
wontons, and white rice.
Aren't you supposed to be on a diet?
You should at least get brown rice.
I don't think so.
I hate brown rice, and I'm so
sick of eating healthy all the time.
I've been eating so much salad.
I swear I've forgotten
what meat tastes like.
There's no better remedy than some
nice, greasy, calorie-laden Chinese food.
I might even get in order of broccoli beef.
Oh, gosh.
I'm so hungry.
Let's call the waitress over.
All right.
We're back.
So now let's take a
look at those delicious
American Chinese dishes on
language takeaway part two.
Language takeaway.
And so here we are with a number
of delicious and very appetizing dishes.
These are things that you'll normally
find in an American Chinese restaurant.
The first one is called Crab Rangoon.
Okay, so this doesn't
sound very Chinese at all.
Now Rangoon is actually a city in a
country called Myanmar, or Burma.
And Crab Rangoon is a special deep fried
dish that's like deep fried dumplings.
But on the inside, there's
cream cheese and crab.
Crab meat.
That's right.
It's kind of, as you said, like a dumpling,
but inside you have cream cheese and crab.
Right.
All right.
Very good.
Now, they also talked about getting
the sesame chicken with fried rice.
Okay.
So sesame is a very common
ingredient in cultures all over the world.
And sesame is a kind
of seed, but some people
also use some sesame
oil in their cooking.
And so these all come
from these white, small seeds.
And sesame chicken is a kind of
chicken that's cooked with sesame seeds.
Okay.
Very good.
Basically, we know what fried rice is.
You just take, it's
just basically rice in a
pan with sometimes a little bit of
meat and egg and just fry it all together.
But what about spring rolls?
I think these are one of the typical
Chinese dishes that everyone knows.
And actually, it's a Chinese dish as well.
I love spring rolls, although I've never
gotten an American spring roll in China.
The spring rolls we're talking
about here are basically wrappers.
These like wonton wrappers that are stuffed
with meat and vegetables and they're rolled
up so they look like a long
roll and they're deep fried.
So okay.
So spring rolls are,
as you said, little rolls
with meat and sometimes
vegetable inside.
Not really sure why they
call it spring roll though.
I don't know either.
Maybe it has to do with the ingredients
like they're vegetables from the spring.
Maybe.
Now, another one that I actually
really, really like is this egg drop soup.
This is delicious.
This is a very simple soup
and the, when you're cooking
it, you break an egg and the
egg is mixed into the soup.
So it looks like it's
kind of got these
yellow pieces floating, but it's a
really nice simple soup with egg.
Okay.
And that's what it's called egg drop soup.
Now you mentioned the wonton wrappers
and they also mentioned fried wontons.
What are wontons?
Okay.
This is a special kind of dumpling.
It's got a piece of
dough basically that's
flattened out and inside there's
meat, maybe some vegetables.
And sometimes you eat it in soup.
But here we're talking about
fried wontons, deep fried wontons.
So you put them in
the deep fryer and their
fried so that they're crunchy
and the insides are soft.
Actually, this is one
of my favorite dishes.
The original one in
China though, as you
said the hunton,
because it's like in a soup.
Yes.
And it's very simple,
but you have like
dumplings in a soup, but the
fried ones are also very, very good.
They are both delicious and
this is making me very hungry.
So maybe we should
listen to our dialogue again.
Hi, welcome to Happy Buddha.
Can I get you anything to drink?
Coke for me please.
I'll have a Sprite.
Okay.
I'll go get that for you.
Are there any questions with the menu?
Do you use MSG?
No, ma'am.
We are MSG free.
Oh, man, I haven't had
Chinese food in so long.
I want everything.
This place has the best sesame chicken.
Yeah, I've been craving
Chinese for such a long time.
I used to get takeout all the time.
It's definitely been a while.
Let's start off with some crab wrangoon.
Oh, yeah, that sounds good.
I think I'm going to get
the sesame chicken with
fried rice, a spring
roll, and egg drop soup.
It's so tempting to order
everything on the menu.
It all looks so appetizing.
I think I'll get general
toast chicken, hot
and sour soup, fried
wontons, and white rice.
Aren't you supposed to be on a diet?
You should at least get brown rice.
I don't think so.
I hate brown rice and I'm so
sick of eating healthy all the time.
I've been eating so much salad.
I swear I've forgotten
what meat tastes like.
There's no better remedy than some
nice, greasy, calorie-laden Chinese food.
I might even get in order of broccoli beef.
Oh, gosh.
I'm so hungry.
Let's call the waitress over.
All right.
We're back.
As we mentioned, these
dishes are very much--
I have a certain American influence
to them, and they're not really spicy.
I think that's the
main difference as well
that American Chinese
food doesn't really have
the intense garlic flavor, nor is
it spicy like usual Chinese food.
That's right.
So I think that part
of that is, like I said,
due to the fact that
a lot of the Chinese
Americans who first
came over came from Hong
Kong and so Hong Kong food
is not as famous for its spiciness.
It's not like sichuan food.
You will see a lot of
sweet sauces, like this
general sauce chicken is
like a very, very sweet sauce.
Right.
It's a lot of soy sauce in American Chinese
cooking, and so these are flavors that are
very, very strong, and
they're not the same
as the Chinese peppers and
these spicy foods you get in China.
That's right.
And actually, there
is one more dish that
we didn't mention in
the dialogue, actually.
But it's very famous all
around the United States.
It's called chop sui.
chop sui.
And many people have argued
about where the name comes from.
Yes.
But chop sui is just basically like everything
chopped up and fried together, right?
It's like stir-fried vegetables and meat
and all put together and just a bowl.
Yeah.
Well, my favorite thing
about the American
Chinese food that we get is
that we get it in these little boxes.
They're very cute and
you take them home and
you open them up and
every food has a box.
And then at the end,
you also get a fortune
cookie, which is a very small cookie
and inside there's a piece of paper.
So don't eat the paper.
And the paper has a fortune for you.
It says, you know, you will be very
lucky today or your favorite number is 17.
Right.
And they're very cute.
Actually, you can see these boxes that
the Catherine mentions on our lesson page.
It's the lesson photo.
And as you said, very, very common,
each dish is put in this little box.
So if you ever get Chinese food, you'll see
people carrying these little boxes around
because they're very
convenient and easy to carry.
But the fortune cookie
thing is also very common.
I was actually very surprised when I went
to China and there were no fortune cookies.
It's weird, isn't it?
I think it's funny because we expect
these things to be very Chinese.
But in fact, when you come to mainland
China, they don't have fortune cookies.
So I think it's a nice surprise,
but also kind of confusing.
That's right.
Well, a very interesting
topic and in the
future, we're going to continue doing
different lessons about different cuisines.
We have Italian food
coming up sometime soon.
So that's going to be very good as well.
And of course, if you
have any lesson suggestions
or maybe you want
to suggest the cuisine
from your country, you
can visit our website, www.
EnglishPod.com and
leave your comments there.
We hope to see you guys
there and until next time.
Bye.